Guide to the Chiapas Media Project Records TAM.774
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Chiapas Media Project Records
1995-2011
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Halkin, Alexandra
Chiapas Media Project
TAM.774
12.25 Linear Feet in 15 manuscript boxes, 6 cassette boxes, 1 record carton, 2 flat boxes, and 1 rolled banner
1.41 Gigabytes in 202 computer files
224 MiniDV
7 DVCAM
1 audiocassettes
1 Betacam_SP
25 VHS
29 Hi8
1 DVDs
The Chiapas Media Project, founded in 1998 by Alexandra Halkin and Paco Vazquez, facilitated the production and distribution of media through four regional media centers built and equipped in collaboration with the Zapatista communities in Chiapas, Mexico. The Chiapas Media Project Records (dated 1995-2011) consist of materials created and collected by Chiapas Media Project documenting its ongoing operations, film and video production and distribution, participation in film festivals, and engagement with indigenous communities. Materials in this collection include video recordings; correspondence with speakers, filmmakers, and festival organizers; newspaper and magazine clippings; academic research; notes and notebooks for the organization's projects; distribution and festival ephemera; and objects, including a banner, t-shirts, and badges and press passes from festivals and conferences.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to Box 15 is restricted until 2097.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Alexandra Halkin in August 2018 and March 2020; the accession numbers associated with this gift are 2018.134, 2021.034, and 2021.074.
Appraisal
During processing an archivist identified published books and personal documents. These materials were removed from the collection, deaccessioned, and offered back to the donor by a curator in 2022.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series, one of which is further arranged in to sub-series. The contents of each series or sub-series are arranged alphabetically. The series and sub-series arrangement of the records is as follows:
Series I: Video Archive
Sub-Series I.A: Guerrero
Sub-Series I.B: Guggenheim Interviews
Sub-Series I.C: Jornaleros
Sub-Series I.D: Living Juarez
Sub-Series I.E: TV Serrana
Sub-Series I.F: Zapatista Communities
Sub-Series I.G: La Mala Cosecha (The Bad Harvest)
Series II: Film Festivals and Screenings
Series III: Community Organizing
Series IV: Written Works.
Historical Note
The Chiapas Media Project, founded in 1998 by Alexandra Halkin and Paco Vazquez, facilitated the production and distribution of media through four regional media centers built and equipped in collaboration with the Zapatista communities in Chiapas, Mexico. The Chiapas Media Project collaboratively produced 32 documentaries for international distribution, largely authored by community members themselves. The films, which focus on issues such as indigenous sovereignty, indigenous cultural practices, environmental sustainability, sustainable food practices, and autonomous education, have been screened at over 120 film festivals in 20 countries between 1998 and 2010, as well as many college and university campuses and other locations across the globe. The Chiapas Media Project is now known as Promedios de Comunicación Comunitaria, and has been a part of the Americas Media Initiative since 2010. Promedios continues to work with indigenous and non-indigenous communities in Southern Mexico providing audiovisual training and technical support.
Custodial History
At the time of accessioning, some audiovisual materials were separated from the archival collection to be bibliographically cataloged and included in the Indigenous Media Collection. Those items were later reincorporated into the Chiapas Media Project Records.
In 2022, NYU Libraries loaned 34 videotapes to Alexandra Halkin. The recordings were returned in January 2026 and incorporated into the processed collection.
Audiovisual Access Policies and Procedures
Audiovisual materials have not been preserved and may not be available to researchers. Materials not yet digitized will need to have access copies made before they can be used. To request an access copy, or if you are unsure if an item has been digitized, please contact Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives, special.collections@nyu.edu, 212-998-2596 with the collection name, collection number, and a description of the item(s) requested. A staff member will respond to you with further information.
Born-Digital Access Policies and Procedures
Advance notice is required for the use of computer records. Original physical digital media is restricted.
An access terminal for born-digital materials in the collection is available by appointment for reading room viewing and listening only. Researchers may view an item's original container and/or carrier, but the physical carriers themselves are not available for use because of preservation concerns.
Scope and Contents
The Chiapas Media Project Records (dated 1998-2011) consist of materials created and collected by the media organization documenting its ongoing operations, film and video production and distribution, participation in film festivals, and engagement with indigenous communities. Materials in this collection include video recordings; correspondence with speakers, filmmakers, and festival organizers; newspaper and magazine clippings; academic research; notes and notebooks for the organization's projects; distribution and festival ephemera, including brochures, programs, posters, and catalogs; and objects, including banners, t-shirts, name badges and press passes from festivals and conferences. The collection documents the ongoing activities of the Chiapas Media Project; the ability of indigenous and other marginalized communities to advocate for themselves through media; and topics and issues concerning indigenous human rights documented in individual works, such as agricultural collectives, indigenous land ownership claims, environmental sustainability, and the Zapatista indigenous movement.
Mass media -- Political aspects -- Latin America; Latin America -- Politics and government -- 20th century.; Latin America -- Politics and government -- 21st century; Indigenous peoples and mass media -- Mexico; Indigenous films; Indigenous peoples -- Civil rights; Indigenous peoples -- Politics and government; Environmental justice.; Agricultural laborers -- Labor unions -- Organizing; Video recordings -- Political aspects; Film festivals.; Halkin, Alexandra; Americas Media Initiative; Ejército Zapatista de Liberación Nacional (Mexico)
- Series I. Video Archive, 1995-2009; 3.5 Linear Feet in 1 record carton, 1 manuscript box, and 5 cassette boxes; 224 MiniDV; 25 VHS; 1 audiocassette; 1 Betacam_SP; 2 DVCAM; 1 DVDs
  Scope and Contents
  This Series contains videos produced by Chiapas Media Project in collaboration with indigenous community members in Mexico and across the Americas from 1998 to 2009. The video recordings include interviews, footage of daily life, and documentaries focusing on issues such as indigenous sovereignty, labor organizing, environmental sustainability, sustainable food practices, autonomous education, resistance to military brutality, and the Zapatista movement.
  In addition to the videotapes, this Series contains documentation of videotape sales, licensing contracts, and video covers.
  Arrangement
  The Sub-Series and video titles were taken directly from inventories supplied by the donor and edited minimally with additional information from video labels. Within their Sub-Series, videos are arranged alphabetically.
  - Sub-Series 1.A: Guerrero, 2005
    This Sub-Series contains work produced by Chiapas Media Project in Guerrero, Mexico.
    - Radio Nomanda: The Word of Water, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_001)
      Radio Ñomndaa is an indigenous community radio station that began broadcasting in December 2004 in the Mexican state of Guerrero. In both Ñomndaa and Spanish, the station transmits the customs and traditions of the Nanncue Ñomndaa, rooted in respect and recognition for the region's cultural diversity.
  - Sub-Series 1.B: Guggenheim Interviews, 2005-2006
    This Sub-Series contains video interviews with indigenous filmakers in Latin America, which Alexandra Halkin conducted with funding from the Guggenheim Foundation.
    - Ana Vilacama - Bolivia, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_003)
    - Ana Vilacama y Marcelina Cardenas - Bolivia, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_004)
    - Camara 2 Fabiola, Crisanto y Juan, Undated (Box 23, Vhs 774_232)
    - Compañeros - Garrucha y Roberto Barrios, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_005)
    - Compañeros - Oventic y Garrucha, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_006)
    - Compañeros - Roberto Barrios y Morelia, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_007)
    - Dante Cerano 1 - Michoacan, August 4, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_008)
    - Dante Cerano 2 - Michoacan, August 4, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_009)
    - Fabiola Crisanto, Undated (Box 23, Vhs 774_230)
    - Guillermo Monterforte 1 - Oaxaca, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_010)
    - Guillermo Monterforte 2 - Oaxaca, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_011)
    - Guillermo Monterforte 3 - Oaxaca, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_012)
    - Ivan Sanjines, Reynaldo Yajra y Marcelina Cardenas - Bolivia, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_013)
    - Jeremias Tunubala - Bogota, Colombia, February 12, 2005 (Box 18, Audiocassette 774_014)
      Created by Asociacion de Medios de Comunicacion Indigena de Colombia
    - Jesus Tapia y Gumercindo Yumani - Bolivia, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_015)
    - Juan Jose Garcia 1 - Oaxaca, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_002)
    - Juan Jose Garcia 2 - Oaxaca, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_016)
    - Juan Jose Garcia 3 - Oaxaca, 2005 (Box 18, Minidv 774_017)
    - Lucila Lema y Tomas de Pasos - Pueblo Oravalo, Ecuador, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_018)
    - Mariando Fabiola, Undated (Box 23, Vhs 774_229)
    - Mirada, Crisanto Manzano, Undated (Box 23, Vhs 774_231)
    - Rebeca Llasa, Pacha Cabascango y Heriberto Gualinga - Quito, Ecuador, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_019)
    - Teco Guarani, Abel Ticona, Ivan Sanjines - Bolivia, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_020)
  - Sub-Series 1.C: Jornaleros, 2006-2009
    These videotapes are source material for Migrar o Morir: Jornaleros Agricolas en los Campos Toxicos de Sinaloa (Paying the Price: Migrant Workers in the Toxic Fields of Sinaloa), as well as other videos relating to labor organizing and migrant working conditions.
    - Abel - DF, November 8, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_021)
      Content description: "Imagenes de la calle"
    - Albel - Barbara, July 11, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_022)
    - Alejandro Cruz Centro de Acopio - Sinaloa, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_023)
    - Augustina - Ayotzinapa, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_024)
    - Augustina 2 - Ayotzinapa, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_025)
      Content description: "JJ3A, #3, Casa de Maria, Mujeres Bordando"
    - Ayotzinapa, Guerrero - C1, Panteon, Procesion de la iglesia, November 1, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_026)
    - Ayotzinapa, Guerrero - C2, Baile-Boda, Campo-Pastoreo de las vacas, October 26, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_027)
    - Ayotzinapa, Guerrero - C3, Boda, Pueblo, Iglesia, Musicos en la Calle, Baile-Pastel, October 19, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_028)
    - Ayotzinapa, Guerrero - C5, Dia de los Muertos, Panteon, October - November, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_029)
    - Baile de Boda, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_030)
      Content description: "C4, Continua Boda (27/Oct/06) y llevan plores al panteon La Lena"
    - Boda de Carmelo y Clara Vargas, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_031)
    - Buen Año 2 - Culiacan, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_032)
    - Camara de Apoyo, 2010 (Box 18, Minidv 774_033)
    - Campo - El 48 2006, November 27, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_034)
      Content description: "Llegada a los campos, niños bañandose, limpiando gales/mujer platica, niños jugando futbolito, niñas lavando/bailando, basura, tienda, videojuegos, platica con Natalia, reparticion de gas, bañando niño, explicando Margarita a mujeres y subiendo al bus"
    - Campos Agricolas 1, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_035)
      Content description: "R3, Galeras, Fumigando, Jornaleros con refrescos, Bebiendo agua, Corte de vegetales, Seleccion y aromado vegetales, Niños del campo, Niños enfermos de los ojos, Amamantando niño, Subiendo al bus, Galeras, Subiendo hacia"
    - Campos Agricolas 2, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_036)
      Content description: "R4, Corre vegetales, Mujeres cargando niños y trabajando, Niños trabajando, Empacando vegetales, Niños comiendo en el campo, Mujer amamantando, Familias comiendo, Cargando vegetales a camion, Subiendo al bus (Termino de jornada), Atardecer, Niños en canal, Ho... cortar"
    - Campos Empacadoras, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_037)
      Content description: "R5, Lavando en canales, Mujeres bañandose en los canales, Descarga de cajas a bandas de empacado, Lavado de vegetales, Trailers cargados, Tranguis en los campos y filas para cobro"
    - Chinatown NYC, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_038)
    - Cruz Salgado Paris, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_039)
    - Delfino 1 - Ayotzinapa, July 14, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_040)
    - Delfino 2 - Ayotzinapa, July 14, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_041)
    - Entrevistas - Sinaloa, November 5, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_042)
    - Fiesta San Lucas - Cacahuatepec, October 17, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_043)
    - Fiesta Santiago, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_044)
      Content description: "Tenango, Baile"
    - Grabaciones realizadas por la familia de Ayotzinapa, November, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_045)
    - Grabaciones realizadas por la familia de Ayotzinapa 2, November, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_046)
    - Guerrero - Culiacan, November 26, 2006 (Box 18, Minidv 774_047)
      Content description: "R2, Hombres platicando, Parada en una tienda, Comida en restaurant, Descanso, La cocina del restaurant, Niño grabando en cocina, Comida, Condiciones del WC"
    - Ingeniero Jorge - Caades, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_048)
    - Jornaleros - Agricola, JJ1, KCT 1, April 12, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_049)
    - Jornaleros - Agricola, JJ2, April 12, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_050)
    - Jornaleros - Agricola, JJ3, April 13, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_051)
    - Jornaleros - Agricola, JJ4, April 13, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_052)
    - Jornaleros - Agricola, JJ5, April 13, 2007 (Box 18, Minidv 774_053)
    - Jornaleros - L1, Undated (Box 18, Minidv 774_054)
    - Jornaleros - L2, February 2, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_055)
    - Jornaleros - L3 (Box 19, Minidv 774_056)
    - Jornaleros - L4, March 19, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_057)
    - Jornaleros - L5, March 28, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_058)
    - Jornaleros - L6, April 1, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_059)
    - Jornaleros - L7, April 11, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_060)
    - Jornaleros - W7, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_061)
    - Jornaleros 1, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_062)
    - Jornaleros 2, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_063)
    - Jornaleros Master 2, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_064)
    - La Abuela, November, 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_065)
      Content description: "La abuela, La iglesia, Los animales, La boda"
    - Let y Luciano, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_066)
    - Marcos Matias - Mexico City, August 11, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_067)
    - Margarita - Ayotzinapa, July 14, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_068)
    - Margarita - DF, November 7, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_069)
    - Margarita - Tlapa, July 14, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_070)
    - Maria - Ayotzinapa, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_071)
    - Matilda - Ayotzinapa, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_072)
    - Micaela - Ayotzinapa, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_073)
    - Micaela y M... - Ayotzinapa, July 13, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_074)
    - Migrar o Morir (Paying the Price), August 14, 2009 (Box 23, Dvcam 774_226, 774_227, Box 19, Minidv 774_079)
    - Migrar o Morir (Paying the Price) Generic Master, October, 2009 (Box 19, Minidv 774_080)
    - Migrar o Morir (Paying the Price) Master, 2008 (Box 19, Minidv 774_075, 774_081)
    - Migrar o Morir (Paying the Price) Planning and Budget Documents, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Migrar o Morir (Paying the Price) Production Receipts, 2006-2007 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Natalia, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_076)
      Content description: "R7, Venta de estereos, entrevista Natalia, cassette virgen"
    - Natalia y Agustina - Ayotzinapa, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_077)
    - Pat Diaz - Oaxaca, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_078)
    - Pedro Vargas y Diego Vasquez - Ayotzina, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_082)
    - Procesion de San Francisco, October 2, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_083)
    - Procesion de San Salvador, May 8, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_084)
    - Procesion de Santiago, July 24, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_085)
    - Rocio y Fua - Ayotzinapa, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_086)
    - Salida de Ayotzinapa, November 25, 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_087)
      Content description: "R1, Escenas de la vida diaria, Casa de contratista, Saliendo de casa, Subiendo a pasajera, Esperando bus, Subiendo cosas al bus, Subiendo personas al bus, Niño con camara"
    - San Lucas - Cacahuatepec, October 17, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_088)
    - Sr Delfino - Ayotzinapa, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_089)
    - Taller, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_090)
    - Taller 1 - Guerrero, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_091)
    - Taller 2 - Ayotzinapa 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_092)
    - Taller 2 - Guerrero, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_093)
    - Taller 4-5 - Guerrero.jpg, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_094)
    - Taller Guerrero 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_095)
    - Toronto 1, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_096)
    - Toronto 2, Undated (Box 19, Minidv 774_097)
    - Untitled - Ayotzinapa, July 13, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_098)
    - Victor - 23 de marzo, March 23, 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_099)
    - Victor - 4 de diciembre, December 4, 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_100)
    - Victor - 4 de marzo, March 4, 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_101)
    - Victor - 9 al 11 de octubre 2006, October 9-11, 2006 (Box 19, Minidv 774_102)
    - Victor - Tlapa, 2007 (Box 19, Minidv 774_103)
  - Sub-Series 1.D: Living Juarez, 1998-2009
    Living Juarez: Collateral Damage in Mexico's Drug War tells the story of the victims of Mexican President Felipe Caldaron's drug war, as well as community organizers in the Villas de Salvarcar neighborhood who protested the abuses committed by armed forces against civilians. These videotapes contain source material for the 25 minute film, which was produced in 2010, and other related videos.
    - Alcides/Luz Ma Federales, October, 2009 (Box 19, Minidv 774_104)
    - Bridge, Street, Cereso e Israel, October, 2009 (Box 19, Minidv 774_105)
    - Caracoles: Nuevos Caminos De La Resistencia (Caracoles: New Paths of Resistance), 2003 (Box 19, Minidv 774_106, 774_107, 774_108, Box 20, Minidv 774_109)
    - Caracoles: Nuevos Caminos De La Resistencia (Caracoles: New Paths of Resistance) Spanish Transcripts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Chiapas 1, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_110)
    - Chiapas 4, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_113)
    - Chiapas 5, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_114)
    - Chiapas 7, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_115)
    - Chiapas 8, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_116)
    - Chiapas 10, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_111)
    - Chiapas 11, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_112)
    - Chiflon 3, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_117)
    - Cuando la Justicia se Hace Pueblo, 2002 (Box 20, Minidv 774_118, 774_119)
    - Cucapas and Kiliwas 9,000 Years Later, 2008 (Box 20, Minidv 774_120)
    - El Curandero (The Healer), 1999-2000 (Box 21, Minidv 774_181, 774_182, Box 20, Minidv 774_126)
    - Defending the Forest: The Struggle of the Campesino Environmentalists of Guerrero (La Lucha por los Bosques), 2000 (Box 20, Minidv 774_121, 774_122)
    - Defending the Forest: The Struggle of the Campesino Environmentalists of Guerrero (La Lucha por los Bosques) Description and Budget, 2000-2001; TW_TAM_774_ER_2
    - Defending the Forest: The Struggle of the Campesino Environmentalists of Guerrero (La Lucha por los Bosques) Licensing Contract, 2001-2005 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - Defending the Forest: The Struggle of the Campesino Environmentalists of Guerrero (La Lucha por los Bosques) Research, Scripts, and Budget Documents, 2001-2002 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Defending the Forest: The Struggle of the Campesino Environmentalists of Guerrero (La Lucha por los Bosques) Transcriptions in Spanish, circa 2000-2005; cuid45230 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Paper Documents (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Electronic Records, TW_TAM_774_ER_3
    - Don Martin y Dona Silvia at Border, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_123)
    - Dona Silvia y Gustavo en Coche, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_124)
    - Education in Resistance, 2000 (Box 20, Minidv 774_125)
    - El Esfuerzo de los Indigenas de Mut Vitz, 2000 (Box 20, Minidv 774_127)
    - El Paso 1, Beto O'Rourke, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_129)
    - El Paso 2, Beto O'Rourke, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_130)
    - El Paso 3, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_131)
    - Eye Dream 1 World Description, 2001; TW_TAM_774_ER_1
    - Eyes on What's Inside: The Militarization in Mexico (Mirando Hacia Dentro), 2004 (Box 20, Minidv 774_133, 774_134, 774_158, 774_159, 774_160)
    - Feds, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_135)
    - Gaby y Juarez, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_136)
    - Guadalupe, MAQs, Street, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_137)
    - Guadalupe, Market, Parking Lot, Burritos, MAQ's, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_138)
    - La Guerra del Miedo (The War of Fear), Undated (Box 20, Minidv 774_139, 774_147)
    - La Guerra del Miedo (The War of Fear) English and Spanish Transcripts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - Gustavo y Julian at Villas de Salvalcar, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_140)
    - El Huerto de Zapata (Zapata's Garden), 2002 (Box 21, Minidv 774_208, 774_209, 774_210, 774_211, Box 20, Minidv 774_128)
    - Irma Casas 2 B-Roll MAQ's, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_142)
    - Israel Arzate Wounds e Irma, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_143)
    - Israel Arzate y Angel, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_144)
    - Kermes Villas / Julian y Guadalupe (Estetica), October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_145)
    - La Familia Indígena (Indigenous Family), Undated (Box 20, Minidv 774_141)
    - La Familia Indígena (Indigenous Family) y Proyecto de Medios, 1998; cuid36504 (Box 20, Minidv 774_146)
    - La Familia Indígena (Indigenous Family) Interview Transcripts in English, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Lanita, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_155)
    - Letters for our Words: Steps Towards Autonomy, 2006 (Box 20, Minidv 774_156)
    - Living Juarez Production Contract, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Living Juarez Production Receipts, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - La Lucha del Agua, 2005 (Box 20, Minidv 774_148)
    - MAQ's y Don Alfredo, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_157)
    - Mujeres Unidas (Women United), 1999 (Box 20, Minidv 774_161, Box 21, Minidv 774_204)
    - Mujeres Unidas (Women United) Licensing Contract, 2000 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Ojo de Agua Communication, Undated (Box 20, Minidv 774_162)
    - La OMC: un peligro para los pueblos, 2003 (Box 20, Minidv 774_149)
    - Palabras Zapatistas Contra la Injusticia (We Speak Against Injustice), 2002 (Box 20, Minidv 774_163, Box 21, Minidv 774_202, 774_203)
    - Palabras Zapatistas Contra la Injusticia (We Speak Against Injustice) Licensing Contract - Sundance Channel, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - The Path of the Mayos with the Other Campaign, Undated (Box 21, Minidv 774_185)
      Master, English Subtitles
    - Paty y Alcides, October, 2009 (Box 20, Minidv 774_164)
    - Policia Comunitaria, Undated (Box 20, Minidv 774_165, 774_166)
    - Promocion del PMC, Miradas 2, Undated (Box 21, Minidv 774_167)